Dr. Khalifa: أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
God ALONE
Verse 11 says,
[39:11] Say, "I have been commanded to worship GOD, devoting the religion absolutely to Him alone.
[39:12] "And I was commanded to be the utmost submitter."
[39:13] Say, "I fear, if I disobeyed my Lord, the retribution of a great day."
[39:14] Say, "GOD is the only One I worship, devoting my religion absolutely to Him alone.
These are all commandments from God to you.
I'm gonna read them again, starting at 11.
God is telling you to say,
[39:11] ..."I have been commanded to worship GOD, devoting the religion absolutely to Him alone.
So, there is no room for Jesus or Moses or Muhammad or the saints.
Huh? Yes.
[39:12] "And I was commanded to be the utmost submitter."
The utmost submitter never complains.
It's a sign of submitter or not.
The utmost submitter is content with whatever God gives him and understands.
13,
[39:13] Say, "I fear, if I disobeyed my Lord, the retribution of a great day."
Submitters also realize that everything has a price.
And this is now after passing all the tests. And you...
You've passed your final test. You're in good shape. And you cannot deviate outside
the path that God drew for you.
Because if you deviate, it's very expensive.
It seems out of proportion, but really it is not.
You know, when I got pinched in the past, I'd say "No! This is too much! I didn't do that bad.
And the answer would come back "yes."
This is it. You didn't do too bad, but this is the price for it. Yeah.
The pinch is always way out of proportion, it seems.
I guess because, you know, somehow we grew up with the notion that God is Forgiving, Merciful
which is true, but we tend to abuse this.
Son.
God wants to make you perfect.
And the system that I have noticed personally, and maybe you too, is that God will take one of
your defects at a time.
And He will keep after you until you get rid of that defect.
Then, He will start another one, until you cleanse out of that one.
The end result is a perfect human being, if there is such a thing.
You'll be following God's commandments perfectly. And you'll be a perfect human being.
So, the utmost submitter understands all these things.
Remember that the utmost submitter has a perfect life.
The only reason you have a headache is because of something you have done.
I don't think there are any exceptions to that. There are no exceptions.
You don't get a scratch or a headache without something you have done.
So, it behooves you to find out what it is that you have done.
Don't defend yourself either.
I used to laugh when I tell some people "what did you do wrong?"
"I didn't do anything wrong." You know, they become defensive.
I say "hey, wait a minute, you're supposed to join me in attacking your "self" and find out what you did wrong."
They become very defensive.
But we're supposed to do this ourselves.
We have to find out what did I do wrong.
But if I, if I'm too egotistic to pinpoint what I did wrong, then I just go on.
Because the punishment will continue until you know what it is.
When you know what it is and you repent, it never happens again.
The problem is solved.
So an utmost submitter means no problems of any kind.
It's almost unbelievable.
But you see, God taught us repeatedly.
God used me as a guinea pig, a happy guinea pig.
I mean, I put myself in situations where a problem should have happened.
But it wasn't the cause of God, so a problem didn't happen.
And the reason I'm saying this is because Ihsan is sitting here, and she expected a big problem.
Thank you.
I had... I was busy with this translation, and I slept here three nights in a row. I didn't go home for three days.
And then, the answering machine... the telephone rang, the answering machine came on. My wife was on the phone.
This is Stephanie. So, Ihsan started to run away.
She said "this is it." She's gonna divorce you. You're finished.
This is it. A big fight.
So, as she was approaching this door here to run away, she heard her say "I made a batch of Italian cookies, but they were so delicious.
I'm sorry we finished all of them. So, I'm gonna make you another batch."
She couldn't believe it.
She, until now, she can't believe it.
But this is... God manipulates the minds and the hearts of the people.
In fact, this happened again when three or four weeks ago...
Huh? A few days ago when this visit.
I slept here two nights in a row.
And she called.
What did she say this time?
What did she want?
No, say it again. What did...
I want to chat.
I forget what she wanted, but it was peaceful. She was also running away.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
She said "I'm the happiest person in the world."
I said "what?"
Now, now I, I was insulted.
"Ok. Wait a minute."
Honest, this is what she said. Yes, I remember now.
She said "I'm the happiest person in the world."
I said "what's happened?"
She said "I found the car I've been looking for, for a long time."
"I'm like a baby. I'm like a child who found a toy."
This is exactly what she said.
She's been looking for a car.
So, I mean, this is a situation that warrants a problem, right, with most people.
"Where have you been?"
"You're a half hour late."
"If you left your office at 2:30, you should have been here at 3 o'clock. It's 4 o'clock now."
So, what I'm saying is that God's Mercy and Grace allowed us to learn from experience.
We really have a track record.
And it is... Edip is not comfortable with my statements.
Because you have to go through what I went through.
When I make a blank statement, blanket statement.
"A believer has a perfect life. No problems, no headaches, no traffic tickets."
He says, he always says "What if we grow and we have a lot of people and problems happen?"
They don't happen. God can handle them.
God's law is absolute.
Let me just read it with you again.
Because I wanted to pass this on to the people.
Let's look at 10:62 or 11:62. What is it?
Page 216.
I think Edip will appreciate that because the Arabic is so powerful and he knows it.
He knows the Arabic.
The top of page 216 says,
[10:62] Absolutely, GOD's allies have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
In Arabic,
(10:62) أَلَآ إِنَّ أَوْلِيَآءَ ٱللَّهِ لَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
Very strong Arabic. It says "Absolutely."
I tried to bring it in the English as close as possible.
[10:62] ...GOD's allies have nothing to fear, nor will they grieve.
The next verse identifies who are they.
[10:63] They are those who believe and lead a righteous life.
That's it.
If you believe and lead a righteous life, you have nothing to fear, nor will you grieve.
Why are you peeking through the, why are you peeking through the crack? Come on in.
A woman: Hi. Is it okay?
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, what?
A woman: I had to peek over at the museum and I just wanted to come by to pray.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
That's fantastic.
Number 64 says,
[10:64] For them, joy in this world,...
We don't have to die first before we enjoy Heaven. It happens here.
[10:64] For them, joy in this world, and the Hereafter. This is GOD's unchangeable decree. Such is the greatest triumph.
So, this is it.
God's law.
You have to realize that there is an admission test.
And the admission test is very exacting, very exacting.
It's usually in the first five years after you claim that you've come to worship God alone.
It doesn't mean it will last five years. Don't be scared.
It comes within the...
If you're proven to be a total submitter completely in the first month, then it is over.
But you must realize it happens. And all the while, you're in God's hands.
The test is very tough.
Where is Mahmoud?
Did he leave?
Yes, so, he's going to take his car.
Mahmoud is undergoing a test like this.
He temporarily lost his wife, his kids, his cars, his computers.
And he's very cheerful as you see. But it's all temporary.
Everything will be restored and twice as much.
He knows that.
He's a good believer.
And we know that.
But what I wanna say is that when you have a problem, you understand, you must understand the root of the problem. What is it?
Why am I having this problem? So, if you're not in the admission test, then you did something wrong.
In the admission test, simply, you say that you're gonna worship God alone, and Satan says otherwise.
You know, "Behrouz doesn't mean it. He's just saying that."
And God tells him "OK, you can go and beat him up, but within a limit. You cannot do this and this to him."
So, Satan starts on Behrouz, beats him up, gives him backache, a few other problems.
But it doesn't fear Behrouz. He continues to worship God alone.
Then, he's proven to be worshiping God alone. Then, all the blessings open up.
Just, just watch.
Pardon?
A woman: I also have a cold and fever, you know, I must be (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: You have cold and fever now?
A woman: Yes, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, well, this is part of the fun of traveling, you know.
The only thing wrong that I can think of that you did may be feeling sympathy
for the people who, out of ignorance, were idolizing Muhammad and Ibrahim and so on which is...
A woman: I do feel that they were idolizing (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Well, their judgment is in God's hand. But I don't think...
I think your cold and fever will go away as soon as you're convinced that that was wrong.
You do that.
Just a little principle, a reminder from God to us to make everything right.
But this is a common... By the way, this is a common thing that I went through and everybody goes through
that we feel for our grandparents and so on. They were, they were all nice people. We loved them very much.
And our wishful thinking tells us "maybe, they didn't know or their intention were good" and so on.
A woman: But we have come to know because you have come in our time. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: (unintelligible) and perhaps. they would have believed. Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but...
Dr. Khalifa: No, but see they had the Quran. They had the message there.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, Lisa, you better get going. Yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, but you see, if they deserved better, God would have seen to it that they received the corrections.
A woman: Because exactly this line my father would say, like "if there's a true believer, nothing
A woman: can harm him and God will give him Heaven in this world." Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: And he will enjoy life. There can't be a happier person. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: And he was one (unintelligible) wherever he went. Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
Dr. Khalifa: This, yeah...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, but this is fine, but you cannot generalize it to the population.
If you know a person personally and you see very well that he is worthy of Heaven, he probably did go to Heaven.
Probably God understood his situation.
I'm sure, not probably, I'm sure God understood his situation.
But we cannot generalize this and we cannot sympathize with that
for our own good because if I say "maybe, these people had good intentions" and we defend them, Satan will capitalize on that.
He says "see, he or she is defending the idol worshippers."
A woman: I got a terrible headache yesterday because I was questioning this (unintelligible) about the...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the case of the first cousin. I'm glad, I'm glad you knew that, yeah.
This is a good example, actually.
And 99.9%, this is exactly the connection.
A woman: (unintelligible.) Then, I started to understand. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: And it's wonderful to know that, because you probably never again question the wisdom of the Quran.
A woman: I didn't mean to, but the way I sounded, I probably...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly. It is the way it sounds.
You see, Mrs. Amirali was perfectly innocent when she was talking about those past generations.
But Satan will take that innocent statement and then make a big mountain out of it.
He will actually say "she is defending the idol worshippers."
And there is a law in the Quran that you do not defend idol worshippers, even if they were your parents, your... and so on.
Remember, he's a liar.
Satan is a liar.
And if we don't word our statements carefully, especially when we're touching on the issue of idol worship,
he will take that and will capitalize.
If I say the slightest thing in defense, away from God. So, this is why I don't compromise when they ask me about
white lies and little insurance and things. I don't compromise because if I say anything
that is a little, just slightly away from God's law, Satan will capitalize on it.
And say "see, he doesn't follow your law."
Then, I'll get smashed on the head.
Because God invariably calls Satan's excuses.
And He says "okay, go test him."
Because God puts limits on him.
When He sends him to test you, He puts limits on you.
He says "you can give her a cold and fever, but that's about it. You cannot give her a headache," for example.
We need to understand this mechanism.
We believe in God. God told us "there is Satan." And we need to understand what does Satan do.
We read the other day, some of you were here, some were not, that Satan will come from your right, your left,
from your right, right, left, front and back.
He will come to you from every direction.
And he will exactly catch those sentences that may be misunderstood to mean that you're defending the idol worshippers or deviating from God's law.
And he'll say "this person... ." He will lie.
But he will use your words.
So, we don't wanna give him a chance to do that.
Like Roxana said, she didn't mean to question God's wisdom. She was just discussing the thing intellectually.
But it sounded like, if I didn't know her, I would think she was questioning God's wisdom. "Why didn't God prohibit first cousins?"
"Why are the Christians wiser than God, for example, in prohibiting first cousins marriages?"
Satan will do that.
Satan will say "Roxana means that You're not wise, as wise as the Christians."
Roxana: I think it takes a while before we realize that every letter of the Quran has to be followed, otherwise we makes mistakes. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, exactly. It takes a while.
It takes a while.
Where is Martha?
Martha.
No jumping, honey. Sit down. Sit down. Don't jump.
Shut the door.
Oh, are you there?
Oh, you're praying?
Okay. I just wanna keep the kids under control, because they're jumping now.
A woman: Nora, thank you.
Dr. Khalifa: Mrs. Amir-Ali is not supposed to have a headache or cold or flu or anything like that.
I think also we have to realize the limitations of our bodies, I guess.
Dr. Khalifa: No, I don't wanna compromise with that. A woman: No, no.
Behrouz: Well, my problem is...
Dr. Khalifa: I just remembered...
Behrouz: My back problem is (unintelligible). I knew that I was not supposed to pick up anything. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Behrouz: But surprisingly, in four days, I didn't have any pain.
Dr. Khalifa: It's just part of the test. You took Mehdi's... Behrouz: Yes. At this time...
Dr. Khalifa: You love him so much that you said "I'm gonna take you backache. Behrouz: Yes.
Behrouz: I don't know if he's gonna love me this much.
Dr. Khalifa: Because it's his anniversary.
God will love you and will remove it.
God loves you and will remove it, IN SHAA ALLAH.
The reason I said... I stopped in the middle of the sentence, we have to realize the limitations of our bodies.
I'm gonna say Alhamdu Lillah, Mã Shã Allãh, Subhan Allah, and all these, because you can brag when you say that.
You give God the credit, you can brag about it.
Brother Abdul Hayy was here, and he came and looked at my computer, my chair.
And he said "you're supposed to have a terrible backache."
Because I'm sitting at the computer, on average, ten hours a day.
He said "this computer is too high or too low. The chair is this and that."
He said "do you have back problems?" I said "no."
He said "you're supposed to." But, so, this is what I mean by even the body limitations.
God will heal you somehow.
You're in your admission test, so don't complain.
You're not complaining. Alhamdu Lillah.
A woman: Ok. Satan (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Mã Shã Allãh.
A woman: (unintelligible) Does he know what is in your mind? But sometimes... Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No, he doesn't know what's in your mind.
A woman: (unintelligible) what you say orally? Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Satan and even the Angels do not know what's in your mind.
But, but, there's a big but.
God knows what's in your mind.
You see, this is at the end of Sura 2.
God is the only one who knows what's in your innermost thoughts.
Not only He knows what's in your mind, He knows what's in your mind ten years from now.
That's in Sura 20.
God knows, He knows what is more secret than the secret.
So, what's more secret than the secret?
The future secret.
So,
So, Satan doesn't know what's in your mind, but God does.
So, and God says "do not have anything wrong inside, inside your mind."
Go ahead.
A man: So, even thoughts that come into your mind, Satan doesn't put them there.
Dr. Khalifa: Your companion does. Yes. Your companion is in there.
And your companion puts those thoughts, and it is your job to sift through them.
And if it's... In fact, remember the verse that says "the believers, when a whisper from the devil comes to them, they seek refuge in God."
Your companion is your devil.
And it's your job to counter those bad thoughts.
He will ask you to do all kinds of bad things, to lie, cheat, lose your temper.
A child: Ok. Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: Does this mean Batul lose her temper? No. No way.
Then, look at her like that.
"Are you telling me that Princess Batul loses her temper? No."
With two kids like that.
A man: So, your companion is not in touch with Satan? Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: He is Satan. He represents Satan.
He already has his built-in natural instinct to tell you not to Pray, not to worship God alone, not to be honest, etc., etc.
It's already, that's his nature.
A man: So, Satan has no... is not in touch with them until...
Dr. Khalifa: That's his seed. That's his seed.
And it's inside your brain. So, this is the, this is the only access he has to your brain.
But it's your job and my job to convert this seed of Satan into a God-worshipping jinn.
A woman: So, it's about your practices in (unintelligible) and living the righteous life that converts Satan?
Dr. Khalifa: See, he's reading the Quran now, as you are reading. She is reading the Quran now, excuse me.
Yeah, as you read the Quran, she too is reading the Quran.
And she's thinking about it.
Edip: You convinced her and him. Now you are beginning to hear it. Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: She tried her best to keep you from doing this. But you won, and you brought her.
Dr. Khalifa: In Sura 72, verse 6, that human beings sometimes use the jinn and they end up in trouble.
And I know some people who used the jinns, and the jinns became their gods.
And on the Day of Judgment, God will ask some of those jinns about that, and they will disown each other.
I know one person who called the jinn jinn, and the jinn said "I am Ali Ibn Abi Taaleb."
And they will ask about these things, you know,
and the jinn will play around with them, will give them information that they actually believe,
And that caused their destruction.
A man: That information (unintelligible) wrong.
Dr. Khalifa: Of course, it's wrong.
A man: They are the big jinn of Ali, for example?
Dr. Khalifa: No, probably not the jinn of Ali, but the companion of Ali.
Because Ali died too long ago.
I haven't heard of a jinn that's 1400 years old.
If the jinns want to play around, they can say anything they want, whatever they say.
If the person is crazy about Elvis Presley, they will come and say "I'm Elvis."
They'll even sing.
Just to fool the humans.
See what can keep the kids quiet? What can you do to keep them quiet?
No, I have a better idea of separating them.
Everybody call your kid next to you.
Let them sit next to you.
They can hear something useful sometimes.
Oh yeah, I've got my kid here.
Okay, Mã Shã Allãh, it's nice and quiet this way.
Yes.
159 says,
[37:159] GOD be glorified; far above their claims. [37:160] Only GOD's servants who are devoted to Him alone (will be saved).
[37:161] Indeed, you and what you worship. [37:162] Cannot impose anything on Him. [37:163] Everyone of you will burn in Hell.
All those people who blaspheme against God and are misled by the jinns, etc. etc.
Those who are not devoted to God alone have chosen, insisted on going to Hell.
The Angels
[37:164] Each one of us has a specific job.
So, when you look at your kid and you say "Mã Shã Allãh." There's an angel specializing in protecting that kid.
"Mã Shã Allãh" invokes that protection.
There's a mechanism for everything.
When you get up in the morning and you say "Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem. La Elaha Ella Allah,"
this invokes an angel to stay with you all day and see to it that you have a nice day.
165, the angels say,
[37:165] We are the arrangers.
Organizers.
[37:166] We have duly glorified (our Lord).
[37:167] They used to say, [37:168] "Had we received the correct instructions from our parents, [37:169] "we would have been worshipers; devoted to GOD alone."
[37:170] But they disbelieved, and they will find out.
Victory for the Messengers Guaranteed
[37:171] Our decision is already decreed for our servants the messengers.
[37:172] They are surely the victors. [37:173] Our soldiers are the winners.
[37:174] So disregard them for awhile. [37:175] Watch them; they too will watch.
[37:176] Do they challenge our retribution? [37:177] When it hits, they will be sorry; they have been warned.
[37:178] Disregard them for awhile. [37:179] Watch them; they too will watch. [37:180] Glory be to your Lord, the great Lord; far above their claims.
[37:181] Peace be upon the messengers. [37:182] Praise be to GOD, Lord of the universe.
You notice the Quran is teaching us to make no distinction among the messengers.
So, God says
[37:181] Peace be upon the messengers.
The next Sura
In the name of God, Most Gracious, Most Merciful
[38:1] S. (Saad),* and the Quran that contains the mathematical code.**
The message, or the miracle.
And the Praying that we went through this today. We looked at the references, and where this word was used.
And it seems to point, among the other things, to the mathematical code of the Quran.
[38:2] Those who disbelieve have plunged into arrogance and defiance.
[38:3] Many a generation before them we annihilated. They called for help, but to no avail.
[38:4] They wondered that a warner should come to them, from among them. The disbelievers said, "he is a magician; a liar.
[38:5] "Did he make the gods into one god?
"Oh, no. How strange."
[38:5] ...This is really strange."
Because every messenger came with the message "there is no god except the one God."
"You must forget about the saints, the prophets, the messengers, as idols."
[38:5] "Did he make the gods into one god? This is really strange."
[38:6] The leaders announced, "Go and steadfastly persevere in worshiping your gods. This is all you need.
[38:7] "We never heard of this from the religion of our fathers. This is a lie.
These are the things that we hear exactly.
[38:7] "We never heard of this from the religion of our fathers...
This is their problem.
And repeatedly, the Quran says "when they are told "follow God's revelations." They say "no, we follow what our parents taught us."
So, one needs to have an open mind and a free freedom.
You can't follow the parents blindly.
There's too much at stake.
And this means perfect happiness here in this world.
There's terrible misery here in this world. Heaven and Hell begin right here.
And all we need to do is step into God's kingdom. Then, we are guaranteed perfect happiness.
You step into Satan's kingdom and you're guaranteed perfect misery.
Even if you make millions and live in mansions and...
What did Christina Onassis do with all her billions?
She tried to commit suicide six times.
Finally, she succeeded and went to Heaven because she was really in... she was... her circumstances.
She was... what is it, abused, oppressed, misguided, mistreated, whatever.
God knows her circumstances.
She died at the age of 38.
But she was a very unhappy person.
How about her father, one of the richest men in the world?
And all, all God did was nullify the muscles in his eyelids.
I mean, these are the weakest muscles in our body.
He couldn't, he couldn't open his eyes.
He was willing to pay a hundred million dollars to fix that.
He couldn't.
He had the scotch tape. He had to keep it completely open all the time.
And this is suffering, you know, because it burns.
Imagine keeping your eyes open all the time. Just try it for two minutes, see what happens.
You cannot do it.
It's the simple design that we take for granted.
But God designed it to clean our eyes, wipe our eyes, and scratch our eyes.
Yes.
But it also moistens our eyes.
There's a continuous flow of liquid in there.
Dr. Khalifa: Are we going with you?
A man: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Alright.
Yeah, go ahead.
The question.
Come, it's your problem.
Thank you, Edip.
173 says,
[37:173] Our soldiers are the winners.
by the way.
The believers are guaranteed victory, guaranteed.
You know, every page of the Quran tells us that God is controlling everything.
It just takes a believer to take advantage of that and enjoy it.
There's a distinction going on between God's kingdom and Satan's kingdom.
God's kingdom is characterized by perfect happiness, perfect health, perfect wealth, perfect peace of mind.
Satan's kingdom is characterized by misery no matter what.
It is proven over and over again that money, power, all the things that people work hard for do not guarantee happiness.
All these people who have attained everything, money, mansion, power, fame, good looks, they come...
The front page is telling us they're unhappy.
So, I think this principle is very well established, that money, power, fame, good looks do not guarantee happiness at all.
There's a statement in Quran says that all happiness is in God's hand, all dignity, happiness is in God's hand, all of it.
And the same expression,
(10:65) ٱلْعِزَّةَ لِلَّهِ جَمِيعًا
Does this mean anything in Farsi?
All Izzat (power) belongs in God's hand.
And God decreed, made a law that He will give it only to the believers.
God controls everything with all the gifts.
"The more you thank Me, the more I give you." God says.
So, what does this mean?
The more we are appreciative, the more God will give us.
If we turn unappreciative, we lose everything.
Just make a point of thanking God every chance you get for everything you have.
Excuse me.
Then, God will give you more.
A woman: (unintelligible) appreciate what God has given us.
A woman: And we praise that, but in the meanwhile we say that "thank you Lord, this is from You."
A woman: (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Sure.
Dr. Khalifa: This is how we thank God for whatever He gave you.
Thank God for your health, for getting your children.
How much would you pay to have (unintelligible) next to you?
A million dollars, right?
I knew of times when you were willing to pay a million dollars for this.
All it took was Surah Al-Hamd.
Yes.
God never turned us down.
How is your back, Mehdi?
(unintelligible)
Behrouz has been carrying furnaces for the last week.
He did it in Stockton and again in Tucson.
So at the end of this session, IN SHAA ALLAH, we read Al-Fãtehah for him and tomorrow he wakes up as good as new, IN SHAA ALLAH.
Yes.
Just take the back pain and throw it away from here.
IN SHAA ALLAH
Oh no worries, they're not disbelievers.
Plenty of them, don't worry.
Number nine says,
[38:9] Do they own the treasures of your Lord's mercy. He is the Almighty, the Grantor.
But number eight, we didn't read yet.
Because they question God's wisdom about choosing His messengers.
Number eight,
[38:8] "Why did the message come down to him, instead of us?" Indeed, they are doubtful of My message. Indeed, they have not yet tasted My retribution.
[38:9] Do they own the treasures of your Lord's mercy. He is the Almighty, the Grantor.
[38:10] Do they possess the kingship of the heavens and the earth, and everything between them? Let them promote themselves.
[38:11] Instead, whatever forces they can muster—even if all their parties banded together—will be defeated.
Look what's happening to communism.
God gave them 40 years of communism to clean out the trinity and then He let them do it.
Perfect plan.
Open up.
Wake up, brother.
Okay, I believe you.
How many years have the East Europe seen communism?
Since 1935?
A man: Since 44, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: 44, yeah.
So, beginning now, the Soviet Union should break up. Did you hear?
A man: Yeah, but the ideology does not break up. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: It's just that they are fed up with the old guys. They want to do away with the old guys.
Dr. Khalifa: And communism. Did you see the Romanian flag?
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah? What does it look like now?
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: He was an opponent of Ceaușescu.
Well, not for long. The communism is out.
Did you say communism succeeded?
A man: They are still in power.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay.
A man: For for human... With human standards. For all political persons, they are still in power. They still control
the secret services. They still control the army. They still control the media. And they control...
Because the people in the streets are socialists. They want socialism to work.
They are disbelievers.
Dr. Khalifa: I see.
A man: And they want socialism to work.
Dr. Khalifa: So, we have to conclude that communism is a success, basically.
A man: The people are still supporting socialism. The people (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: I'm agreeing with you.
Number 11.
[38:11] Instead, whatever forces they can muster....will be defeated.
Number 12.
[38:12] Disbelieving before them were the people of Noah, 'Ãd, and the mighty Pharaoh.
[38:13] Also, Thamoud, the people of Lot, the dwellers of the Woods (of Midyan); those were the parties.
[38:14] Each of them disbelieved the messengers and thus, My retribution was inevitable.
[38:15] These people can expect a single blow, from which they will never recover.
They challenged...
These people I understand to be the Arabs.
And one blow I understand to be an asteroid from space.
IN SHAA ALLAH.
Number 16.
[38:16] They challenged: "Our Lord, why do you not rush the retribution for us, before the Day of Reckoning."
They challenged God.
This is it. We really read two pages and we leave the floor open for questions and discussion.
A man: Why is this the people of the Woods?
Dr. Khalifa: Midyan. Midyan.
This is another name for Midyan.
Which is now Gaza, Gaza Strip.
That's what Midyan is.
A man: In the translation in this (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: So? People of the Woods.
A man: (unintelligible) Woods.
Dr. Khalifa: What is KHASHAB? Do you have KHASHAB in Farsi?
A woman: KHASHAB?
Dr. Khalifa: KHASHAB?
Dr. Khalifa: Wood, what is wood?
A woman: KHASHAB?
A man: CHOOB (چوب)
A child: KHASHAB
A child KHESHAB (gun's magazine)
Dr. Khalifa: He knows.
A woman: He can't take it enough.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok, folks. There's a new word in the Farsi language.
The new generation knows.
Dr. Khalifa: CHOOB (چوب)?
A man: CHOOB (چوب)
Dr. Khalifa: CHOOB (چوب).
So, it will be the people of the CHOOB.
A man: The people of the CHOOB. Ok.
A man: But the Woods here means JANGAL (jungle).
Dr. Khalifa: Not necessarily, no.
A man: Carpenter. Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: They would have been carpenting
A man: NAJJAR. Do you mean carpenter?
Dr. Khalifa: NAJJAR
Dr. Khalifa: Don't call NAJJAR. Whatever the Arabic says.
The people of the Woods.
(38:13) أَصْحَـٰبُ لْـَٔيْكَةِ
A man: لْـَٔيْكَةِ Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: We don't have to put around interpretation. Go ahead.
A man: It's funny when you say "they get tricked by big literaries."
When I was in Tunisia, I was young, I was envious of the Saudis.
So, "they, they are the people who are very closer to God."
Dr. Khalifa: They are the (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. A man: Yes.
A man: Because when they are trying to give us (unintelligible), you don't have to do Ramadan.
A man: So (unintelligible), they are the people (unintelligible). Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You see, having this message creates a great responsibility.
It's a great privilege and a great responsibility.
Because God says that the Jews, for example, are His chosen people.
This is in the Quran a few times.
So, why are they suffering so much?
Why did Hitler kill so many of them?
Why were they scattered all over the world?
Persecuted and discriminated against.
Because of the responsibility. They received the scripture and they didn't follow it.
Now, the Arabs received the Quran, which is a lot more powerful.
It is the complete message.
Every page says "God alone" and they abandoned it. And this is documented in the Quran, in Sura 25.
That they deserted the Quran.
So, you can imagine that their retribution will be a lot worse.
And it's inevitable.
A man: God says in the Quran that He never destroys a land before bringing a messenger.
Dr. Khalifa: The bad signs.
A man: When the messenger comes, (unintelligible) does that land get destroyed? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Yes?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, I can say that 100%.
It's in Sura 17, God says "I will not send a retribution before I send a messenger.
I mean, God made it conditional.
So, all these miracles that are showing up, and the message, and the messenger, mean that there is severe repudiation coming
to the disbelievers.
A man: So, land means, what? (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, there is no land.
A man: They are a native nations.
Dr. Khalifa: No, God left it blank.
He says "we do not...we do not..."
Let's look at Sura 17.
You can see the expression.
I'm trying to find a different quote.
A woman: 15.
Dr. Khalifa: 15?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the end of 15.
It says,
[17:15] ....We never punish without first sending a messenger.
Cause the messenger points out, gives a choice to the people and then they have to make a decision.
After making the decision, they are held responsible for it.
Yes, this life, yes.
It's talking about this world. yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: What's the verse number?
A man: It's 24.
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Why don't you read it?
Go ahead read aloud so everybody can hear you.
A man: 24
(unintelligible) page here 454.
A man: And (unintelligible) 24
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: This is an incident where David was in a sanctuary and these two people went in, snuck in.
with 99 sheep.
Yeah.
They were fighting over one sheep.
Well, actually, there's a great lesson here, but I wonder why did you take this out.
A man: I did it before, actually. 24.
Dr. Khalifa: You don't know what it is? A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: It's just two brothers, two brothers.
One had 99 sheep and the other had one sheep.
God wants to teach us a lesson about being very careful when you judge between the people.
And this... the fellows, they went to David to judge between them.
The fellow with the one sheep said "I have one sheep and he has 99 sheep and he wants to take mine. And he insists on it."
So obviously, the one with the 99 sheep... David said "no, keep your sheep. Don't give it to the fellow. He has with 99 of them. You have only one."
"So, if you give him your sheep, you'll have none and he will have 100. Keep yours."
So, even though this judgment is very clearly fair, David still thought maybe he did the unjust
judgment and he repented and he was asking God for forgiveness and everything.
You can imagine how careful... This is what made David, David.
David is very special in the Quran.
One of the preferred, by God, prophets.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
But this is David's judgment.
Dr. Khalifa: He told the fellow with the one sheep "keep your sheep. Don't give it to him." A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Then, even though this is a very clear and extreme example of a good judgment,
he said "maybe, I did the wrong judgment."
And he was repenting and asking forgiveness and...
I mean, our presidents back home, they kill people.
Then, David just said "keep your one sheep and he keeps his 99."
They kill people, commit murder and they steal billions of dollars.
Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, no he wanted it. He wanted it. Maybe, he wanted to buy it.
A man: No, he won't
Dr. Khalifa: That's okay. They wanted to mix, but he doesn't want to.
The fellow with the one sheep didn't want to do it.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: That's not the point.
Yes.
You got it.
That's correct.
Yes, he waited, yes, yes, this is...
Yeah, he waited, he, he, he waited and he studied and he did everything. And then he judged.
Emily got it.
And that's it.
He was afraid of... he was thinking of God. "Did he do the right judgment?"
Yeah.
Of course.
What would you do?
A woman: I don't know.
Dr. Khalifa: Well,... A woman: I'm not in that situation.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, you are now.
Somebody came to you and he says "I have one sheep and my brother has 99 sheep. And he wants to take my one sheep."
Ok, what would you do?
Do you wanna tell him to give his sheep to the other guy?
A woman: He can give the brother the sheep, but here everyone's money is his own.
If the brother, you know, is giving to his brother, they can make a business (unintelligible).
But if you're going...
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, but the, but this fellow without the sheep, he will just sit there and do nothing.
At least he has one sheep to care about. He will take it in the morning to eat and bring it in the afternoon. And...
It's his job.
Parivash: I have a question. It is my understanding. I don't know if it's true.
About Sura 15 that...
Aya 91, alright? And yeah...
Because of the... remember the first time, the seven pairs.
Ok? And
I think it couldn't be the time of Muhammad but I wanna know that (unintelligible) time of Muhammad and you, but
my understanding is it could be...
Dr. Khalifa: Seven pairs have to do with the end of the world.
Parivash: Okay, no, but after that, it says
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Dr. Khalifa: [15:88] Do not be jealous of what others...
Parivash: Ok. Ok. And after
Parivash: [15:89] And proclaim: "I am the manifest warner."
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: [15:90] For we will also deal with the dividers.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, to accept the Quran partially. Parivash: Ok.
Parivash: If it was time of Muhammad, it would say "And Proclaim I am the messenger."
Dr. Khalifa: I didn't say, I didn't say it was the time of Muhammad.
Parivash: It was the...they accepted Quran only partially. At the time of Muhammad...
Dr. Khalifa: There was no Quran.
Parivash:... complete that...
Dr. Khalifa: Because you're making an assumption that is not there.
Dr. Khalifa: I didn't say it's been the time of Muhammad.
I didn't say it was at the time of Muhammad.
Parivash: It wasn't. It couldn't be at...
Dr. Khalifa: I didn't say that. Where did you get that?
Parivash: No, I think my understanding is wrong. And I wanted your idea.
Dr. Khalifa: No, but does it say in the translation that this is the time of Muhammad?
Parviash: No.
Dr. Khalifa: You're making the wrong assumption and then you're carrying on based on that.
Which happens quite often. Sometimes we make a wrong assumption and then we build on it.
And we keep going on and on.
So I'm stopping you before you go on and on.
What is the footnote?
Parivash: I'm talking about 91. It could be...couldn't be at the time of... now.
Dr. Khalifa: It's applicable also at the time of Muhammad.
But just, I'm leaving it as it is in the Quran.
I see what you mean. In other words, at the time of the Prophet Muhammad, the Quran was not complete.
It was not in this form. Yes.
It has to be now. I see what you mean.
Sorry.
Your chicken kitchen is sometimes confusing.
A woman: We read in the afternoon that...
God, God (unintelligible) but in six days, he made heaven and the earth.
(Unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Because he will not make it until after the judgement.
When all the people are called back
And then the bad ones will go to Hell. So, God doesn't wanna do it now.
He wants to do it afterwards.
God created Heaven. The heavens and the earth are different from Heaven, which is paradise.
God created the heavens and the earth in six days.
But heaven or paradise is different from heaven. You see, the English language confuses it a little bit.
Because there is the heavens and the earth, which were created in seven days. And there is Paradise, which some people also call Heaven.
And this is already in existence.
But Hell will not be created until after the Day of Judgment.
On the Day of Judgment. Good question.
Mã Shã Allãh
See, the children, they pick up things. You think they're sitting there oblivious?
You think this guy is oblivious, but he's observing everything.
Right, Hanan?
Mã Shã Allãh
A man: And Sura 15 says
[15:98] You shall sing the praises of your Lord,...
Is that singing like singing (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, it's the English expression, meaning praise God all the time.
A man: It's not singing.
Dr. Khalifa: If you wanna do it, do it outside of here.
Dr. Khalifa: Mani can put up with that.
Does he sing a lot?
Not even in the shower?
A woman: Rashad, we previously read that Haroot and Maroot (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Magic. Witchcraft.
A woman: But it says also that people used it in a bad way. Does it mean that people can use it in a good way?
Dr. Khalifa: No.
God says "it only brings harm, no good."
A woman: Either way.
Dr. Khalifa: That should not be "abuse."
I don't know. I have to think about it.
Dr. Khalifa: But it's the statement... A man: that the jinns are...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, it's using the jinns. A man: ... on the satanic side.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Parivash: If nobody asks it then I (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: You see, if it's something good, it should be temporary.
Like the psychic who tried to stop the train, remember?
It worked for him for a while, but then, at the course of time, the jinn said "bye."
Usually it's in a bad way. We have to stay away from the jinns, I know.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
It could never have anything to do with jinns.
A woman: Some people are curious about the things that drive them away from God
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Invariably. Yes.
Invariably, it takes them away from God.
A man: So, how come (unintelligible) with the jinns?
God is the One who put them in his service.
God said "I committed the jinns to serve Solomon." Not only the jinns, the jinns, the birds.
Dr. Khalifa: Who? Karim?
Karim.
A woman: Do you mean that convert our jinn by...
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A woman: So, it would be converted and then...
Dr. Khalifa: to be come a good one.
You're converting him right now by reading the Quran.
When you read the Quran and think about it, our jinn is also reading the Quran at the same time and thinking about it.
And your jinn will tell you "don't pray, don't believe this.
"Why go through all the trouble?"
This is his job.
And you tell him "no, I'm gonna Pray five times a day because I want to be happy all my life."
"I'm going to follow this because this guarantees me victory and happiness."
And he tells you "oh, forget it. This is all nonsense."
So, you continue to debate like this until you convert him, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A woman: Then, what happens after that?
Dr. Khalifa: Then, you become friends, become identical.
A man: My question was simple.
When I hear what the jinn power is I believe everything (unintelligible)
I mean, for example. But in the outside, the jinn will...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, the jinn will whisper to you.
A man: (unintelligible) believer Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible) Dr. Khalifa: Right.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The jinn is telling you to sleep. A man: Yeah.
A man: But my question is...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, this is all of us. Our jinn is always telling us to not to, not worship God alone.
A man: You believe all the time "oh, I don't (unintelligible) because I have a challenge between me and him." Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: There'll be a time when, like Karim said, there'll be a time when he's completely converted.
As a matter of fact, he can be ahead of you.
Tomorrow, you're gonna be here for the Khutba, Friday prayer?
A man: Yes. Dr. Khalifa: Yes, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: So, you're gonna hear an example of a jinn that is cooperating with you.
A woman: Our jinn is being Muslim.
Then after that, is that possible that our jinn guide us and...? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes the jinn will be ahead of you.
And the Quran, we were reading yesterday, or the day before yesterday, how God matches your companion,
matches the companion, the jinn and the human companions are matched.
So, if you're destined to believe, God matches a believing jinn with you, who is also destined to believe.
A person who's destined to disbelieve, God will match a disbelieving companion.
Which makes sense.
A man: Rashad, what about astrology? Isn't it a thing that jinn do that?
Dr. Khalifa: No, this is simply observation.
They notice that the sun is in the zodiac and another zodiac this and that, so something happens on earth.
It notices the people who are born under a certain sign, have certain characteristics. So, they made notes.
And they compile them and computerize them.
Then, if you tell me that you're a Libra, I can tell you what your characteristics are.
You're more susceptible to colds and things like that.
They're just observations, Ok, a compilation, but it's very... it has a long way to go.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
Dr. Khalifa: See, we cannot see the jinns. But I guess some manifestations of the jinn, people would think they're ghosts.
Parivash: Rashad, the jinn (unintelligible)
Parivash: And they, in their first life, they say, they totally admitted the Shaytan. Dr. Khalifa: Satan.
Parivash: Our difference is the human and the jinn (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: God gives the jinns a longer life and more ability to fly in the universe and study God's signs.
But the humans are given 7:172.
Read it. 7:172, again.
A man: Rashad, (unintelligible) ability (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, because they already made up their minds very strongly that Satan is right.
See, here, God said to the children of Adam, not the children of Satan, not the jinns.
A man: So, did Shaytan know that he is (unintelligible)? Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Not really, no. It's just that there's a different allegorical Heaven for them. Because...
How do I...
Let us say, compare you with a tree.
You and a tree.
Well, think of it as two creatures.
And I'm saying "I'm gonna put you and the tree, I'm gonna put you both in Heaven.
I'm gonna give you steak. I'm gonna give you potatoes and rice and fruit."
Do you think the tree will go for that?
What? Do you understand what I said?
No, you are a creature and the tree is a creature.
And I'm telling you "I'm gonna put you both in Heaven where you can eat steak every day."
Know what?
A woman: Because the tree doesn't like the steak. Dr. Khalifa: Right.
So, the humans and the jinns are two different creatures.
And God is telling us "I'm gonna put you in gardens with grapes and pomegranates and fruits."
The jinns don't, the jinns don't care about that.
So, God is telling them that "you're gonna have your own Heaven with different things.
A woman: It's actually going to be... Dr. Khalifa: Yes, actually may be the same Heaven.
A woman: Are the plants' souls the same as us? Dr. Khalifa: Uhum.
(unintelligible).
Mã Shã Allãh
(unintelligible)
A woman: The stars and the trees are like me? Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: No.
They're creatures.
Well, it's my sleeping time, brothers and sisters. So, I'm gonna retire and see you in the morning, IN SHAA ALLAH.
People: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: I got up at what time?
A man: This morning?
A man: 4.
Dr. Khalifa: No, it was one o'clock.
A woman: Are you working?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, I left home at one. So, I got here about twenty after one.
This is why people laugh at me when I say "it's my sleeping time."